I am a **Lawyer turned Software Engineer**, having 4 years of legal experience as a corporate and intellectual property attorney. As a Software Developer in a short span of 6 months I've worked on various frameworks/languages like, **JavaScript**, **Golang**, **Python**, **React**, **Next.js**, **Express.js**, **Node.js**, **MySql**, **PostgreSql**, **MongoDB**, **Html & Css** additionally on **GitHub**, **Jira & bitbucket**. I am a highly motivated individual with a track record of success in handling high-stakes matters with precision and efficiency, making me an ideal candidate for any organization looking for a driven, results-oriented individual. Moreover, my aptitude for learning and adapting to new environments allows me to excel in collaborative settings and be a team player.

Link to Linkedin
Link to GitHub

Link to PortfolioWebsite

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION

General Assembly - New York City

Full Stack Developer – Certificate Course	_0
Faculty of Law, University of Delhi LLB – Bachelors in Law – Degree- focus on corporate law, IPR & international contracting	2015-2018
Indian Society of International Law, New Delhi Intellectual Property Law– Post Graduate Diploma- specialization in copyrights, trademarks, traditional knowledge IP & geographical indicators (GI)	2016-2017
Bachelors in Arts, Jagran College of Arts Science & Commerce, CSJMU (Kanpur) University Subjects- Psychology, Political Science and English Literature - focus on world constitutions and polity	2012- 2015

SKILL

- Technical Skills JavaScript, Golang, React, Next.js, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Html, Css, GitHub etc
- People Skills Communications/client-relations, problem-solving, adaptability, flexibility, team-player, time-management
- Language Skills Fluent/Native (English, Hindi, Punjabi) Beginner/Intermediate (French, German, Indonesian)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ayoconnect (Jakarta, Indonesia) - Internship Remote

May 2023 - Present

2022-2023

- Worked on creating a Virtual Card frontend for Client on Next.is
- Worked on Payments Project using Go & Mysql

General Assembly (New York City) - Apprentice

Dec 2022 - March 2023

- Successfully completing 500+ hours of expert-led instruction in **Java Script, Python, Django, React**, Liquid, Node.js, GitHub, HTML & CSS
- Project 5 Developed an E-commerce(clothing) app using (MERN, Stripe Payment Gateway, and npm packages like jspdf, html2canvas, cors etc).
 - The deployed link for stripe payments is still being worked on. But is visible locally if needed. <u>Frontend-readme</u> & Backend-readme
- Project 4 readme- Developed a full-stack Food-Delivery-App for a restaurant using (MongoDB, Express.js, .liquid).
- Project 3 readme Developed Particle-Effect with html canvas and css.
- Project 2 <u>readme</u>- Built a <u>Raven-Hunt-Game</u> using (HTML, CSS, Java Script & Dom manipulation with Vanilla Java Script).
- Project 1 readme Build a <u>Tic-Tac-Toe</u> with Html, JavaScript & Css.

Rouse & Company International - Legal Researcher (Jakarta, Indonesia)

Dec, 2021 -Feb, 2022

• Led research on - Indonesian IP Laws/ court decisions & Law applicable on OTT platforms in Indonesia (eg- Law &

- regulations on Broadcasting/Advertisement/Advertisement/Currency/Payment Gateways/ Competition/ and IT etc)
- Deep **research on NFTs and legal issues** around them (eg- smart contracts, IP Laws, licensing & royalties), also analyzing the impact of NFTs on brand marketing and adjacent copyright/trademark infringements.
- Coordinated with the Global Rouse team and provided research for global projects.

Digi Shares - Legal Researcher Internship (Denmark - remote)

Nov, 2021 -Feb, 2022

- Led various legal researches on topics like- status of crypto-assets, public offers, prospectus requirements under Indian Law and security token offering vehicles in India and offshore.
- Prepared detailed legal reports, memos and updates on legal developments in relation to regulation of crypto-assets and security tokens in various jurisdictions

Independent Practice July, 2020- Oct 2021

Built an independent legal practice spanning **both national & international clients** with a focus on financial regulation, international corporate contracting & litigation

- Led international contracting for a UAE based pharmaceutical firm for their global commercial partnerships
 - o Drafted complex multi-party sales, market authorization and sub-licensing agreements
- Legal research & content creation for top law firms on subjects like Magnitsky Restrictions, international private / public law
 - Led topic expertise on new & upcoming areas of fintech regulation, cryptocurrencies & startup funding
 - Deep research on legal challenges, complexities of startup funding rounds and management of cap tables
- Built a diverse client base by leveraging content created & sourcing cases via international conferences & seminars
- Provided free legal aid/ pro bono cases for socially and financially deprived individuals & families

Nanda and Associates Feb, 2020 -Jan, 2021

- Represented the **Indian Income Tax Department** in criminal proceedings against corporates & private individuals
 - o Includes legal opinions on complex matters related to non-compliance of corporate tax & income tax
- Worked with an International Lawyer from Estonia on multiple international agreements eg. multi-party NDAs, e-contracts
- Led research & content creation on a wide set of international laws
 - Financial laws: Fintech, cyber laws, DTAA (double tax avoidance agreement), CSR (corporate social responsibility)
 - International dispute laws: Territorial disputes, international mandates, international justice system, bilateral trade agreements between different countries, privacy laws etc

Amaanta Legal April,2019- October,2019

- Worked with a corporate client on handling a complex class action lawsuit including multiple types of cases against them
 - Given end to end ownership including conceptualizing legal strategy, drafting arguments, pleading, court appearances, multi-party negotiations etc
 - o Included handling of long standing dispute with another company on distribution of shares & fund siphoning

Internships - AVA Legal, CLRA (Centre for Legislative Research & Advocacy.

2018-2019

OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS & ACTIVITIES

- All India Rank (AIR) 15 in Indian Army Judiciary exam
- Online Courses: WIPO Course on Intellectual Property, University of Pennsylvania Intellectual Property Laws

INTERESTS

• Reading, Organizing, Dancing and Shopping